Remember the "Personality".
牢记“人格”
I met a girl today. Her name is Nevra Elmas.
我今天遇到一个女孩，她叫内夫拉·埃尔马斯
Do you have something to tell me Binnaz?
你有话要跟我说吗？宾纳兹
She is the only one I trust. Because Nevra understands me.
她是我唯一信任的人，因为内夫拉了解我
It's Nevra's birthday today. I got her a present.
今天是内夫拉的生日，我送她一份礼物
Has your brother Tayyar ever mentioned a girl named Reyhan?
你的兄弟塔亚尔有没有提到过一个叫雷汉的女孩吗？
He used to say "they wasted her", not "I wasted her".
他曾经说的是“他们糟蹋了她”，而不是“我糟蹋了她”
I told you, I haven't done anything. I only threw a small piece of stone.
我告诉过你，我什么都没做  我只扔了一小块石头
Me and Nevra share a secret.
我和内芙拉分享了一个秘密
Cemil almost owns whole of Kambura.
塞米尔几乎拥有整个坎布拉
Nothing ever takes place without his knowledge.
如果没有他的话什么事都办不成
If it is as precious as to be hidden under a pillow...
如果它被藏在枕头下  那么珍贵的东西
it was more likely a diary.
它更可能是一本日记
I told Nevra everything. But she doesn't believe me.
我把一切都告诉了内芙拉，但她不相信我
You are not speaking to your friend in Ankara.
你不是在跟安卡拉的朋友通话
I don't think you should ever speak to him again anyway.
我不认为你应该再跟他通话了
Save his a..ss and save your own.
救他一命  也救你自己一命
We need someone to sort him out.
我们需要一个人来解决他
I will burn that gypsy so bad they will ever dare to return to Kambura.
我将把吉普赛人烧死，以至于他们甚至都不敢再回到坎布拉
Tayyar remembers you.
塔亚尔记得你
He said "they wasted the poor girl".
他说：“他们糟蹋了那个可怜的女孩”
Hello Reyhan.
你好雷汉
If Tayyar remembers, so do the others.
如果塔亚尔记得，其他人也记得
All of them, they all remember.
他们所有人，他们都记得
Whole of Kambura remembers.
整个坎布拉都记得
They just pretend that they don't.
他们只是假装自己不记得
Don't pull the trigger.
别开枪
Because I won't.
因为我不会开枪的
The scene will be catastrophic, God forbid if one of these glasses break.
如果开枪的话现场将是灾难性的，如果其中一块玻璃碎了，上帝保佑。
So intriguing.
真有趣
Once I saved a fish's live.
曾经我救了一条鱼
Now they are saving my life.
现在他们救了我的命
I don't think you've come here to kill me anyway.
我不认为你是来杀我的
I tell you what's best...
我告诉你最好的方案……
we both put the guns down...
我们俩都放下了枪
and start from scratch.
从头开始
Right from the beginning.
重新开始
Nevra, where are you?
内芙拉，你在哪里？
I am at the station in Kambura.
我在坎布拉警局
The girl we're looking for is definitely Reyhan.
我们要找的女孩绝对是雷汉
I'll tell you when I come back but I have to stay here another day.
我回来的时候会告诉你，但我不得不在这里再呆一天
Nevra...
内芙拉……
chief Tolga is suspended.
托尔加局长被停职了
Are you serious? Why?
你是认真的吗？为什么？
We don't know.
我们不知道
Nobody knows. Firuz will take his place temporarily.
没有人知道  菲鲁兹会暂时取代他的位置
The chief is packing up today. I think you should be here to say your farewells.
院长今天收拾行囊，我想你应该在这里和他告别
O.K.
好
He tells me to organize a fancy dress party where all the guests are...
他让我组织一次盛装聚会，聚会上所有客人都要……
dressed in " Dog Killer" costumes.
穿着“狗杀手”服装
He says "bring the gun too. I'll be there to finish somebody off".
他说：“还要带上枪，我会在那里杀人的。”
What shall I do? Set up a party?
我该怎么办？举办聚会？
You're right. But let's say we don't cooperate. The guy killed 11 people.
你是对的，但是假如说我们不合作  凶手已经杀死了11个人
Do you think he'd leave me alone?
你以为他会放过我吗？
- Hi guys. - Hi mum.
-大家好-妈妈
Deva...
德瓦
can I talk to you in private?
我可以私下跟你说话吗？
O.K
好
See you later Süveyda.
待会见苏薇达
What is so important?
有什么重要的事吗？
Your dad called.
你爸爸打电话了
What did he say?
他说什么？
He says me misses us.
他说很想念我们
So?
然后呢？
So...
然后……
he wants us back.
他要我们回去
He says he'll book and pay for our flight.
他说他要订票并为我们的航班付款
"Otherwise I'll come and get you myself" he says.
他说：“否则我会过来把票给你。”
So, he is planning to kidnap us.
所以他打算绑架我们
Not exactly. But you know your dad. He can be very impatient.
不完全是  但是你知道你的父亲  他可能会很着急
But he doesn't care about what we want.
但是他不在乎我们想要什么
And what did you tell him?
那你怎么跟他说的？
"Deva started school and I found a job. We have a new life now."
“ Deva开始上学，找到了工作，我们现在有了新的生活”
Didn't you tell him that?
你没告诉他吗？
Of course I did.
我当然告诉他了
But he says "don't worry, school is not a big issue, we'll figure something out".
但是他说：“不用担心，学校不是大问题，我们会解决的”
Mum...
妈……
that's exactly why my dad wanted to get divorced.
这就是为什么我的父亲要离婚
He had enough of you going along with everything he said.
他受够了你对他百依百顺
As if he was your only connection with life.
好像他是你生命中唯一的联系
He was suffocating because you made him feel like...
他几乎要窒息了，因为你让他感到……
the world revolved around him.
世界围绕着他旋转
And now he is upset because we are not there.
现在他很沮丧，因为我们不在那
That's normal, because he's got no one to boss around.
那是正常的，因为那个男人没有别人能指使了
The person you call "that man" is your father. He looked after me.
你叫“那个男人”的人是你父亲  他很照顾我
Your mum is ill, son.
儿子  妈妈病了
I know.
我知道
Your mum is an alcoholic.
你妈妈是酒鬼
I'll still be an alcoholic even if I quit drinking.
即使戒酒，我还是个酒鬼
That's how it will always be.
就是这样
And your father put up with me. He looked after me. Understand?
你父亲能够容忍我  他照顾我  明白吗？
Your illness has got nothing to do with being alcoholic.
你的病与酗酒无关
Your problem is something else.
你的问题是别的
You become the slave of whoever looks after you. That's your illness.
你成为了照顾你的人的奴隶  这才是病根
You are addicted to people, not alcohol.
你沉迷于人，而不是酗酒
Girls!
女孩们！
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
You've said it was impossible. How did it happen?
你已经说不可能了，这是怎么发生的？
I have been looking at the wrong floor.
我一直在错误的看着地板
I should've been looking further up.
我应该一直往上看
- How much further up? - Very much.
-还有多高？-非常非常高
That's why I am telling you the pack it in. Because it's too dangerous.
这就是为什么我告诉你打包的原因，因为太危险了
Do you remember when we were at the university?
你还记得我们上大学的时候吗？
Remember the dreams we had?
还记得我们的梦想吗？
Sure I do. We were planning to change the world.
当然，我们曾计划改变世界
But what happened? We changed our world.
但是发生了什么事  我们改变了我们的世界
I can't breathe here. Not enough oxygen. I want to go back to school days.
我不能在这里呼吸  氧气不足  我想回到学校
It's up to you.
由你决定
What are you going to do now?
你现在要怎么做？
I'll arrest him. What else? Just tell me, is it really him?
我会逮捕他  还有什么？只要告诉我，真的是他吗？
99 percent. But you won't go in alone, will you?
99％的可能性  但你不会一个人进去，对吗？
At least let chief Tolga know.
至少让托尔加局长知道
From now on, I am the one to be reported to.
从现在开始，你向我汇报
Tolga is suspended. I am replacing him.
托尔加被停职了  我要接替他
- Are you serious? - It was inevitable.
-你是认真的吗？-这是不可避免的
Look at me, I am working like a donkey.
看看我，我像驴一样勤奋工作
All Tolga was doing laying on his back.
托尔加什么都没干
You are a dodgy man. You've got it in for Nevra.
你这个狡猾的人  你已经对内芙拉下手了
Didn't you say you'll catch the man before she does?
你不是说你会在她之前先抓住凶手吗？
- See this? - What?
-看到这个吗？-什么？
The mark left by Nevra's slap.
内夫拉的耳光留下的印记
I see it every morning when I look at the mirror.
我每天早晨看镜子时都会看到
It is Zuhal.
是祖哈尔
Strange.
奇怪
Hello? Hi Zuhal.
喂？ 你好 祖哈尔
Yes, he is here.
是的，他在这里
Hang on.
别挂断
O.K darling.
好的，宝贝
Zuhal, how are you sweetheart?
祖哈尔，你好吗？
Pardon?
什么？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
So sudden?
这么突然吗
Dear oh dear!
亲爱的，亲爱的！
Why?
为什么？
O.K, I see.
好的我明白了
We'll talk later.
我们以后再说
O.K, I've got to go.
好啦  我挂了
My silly daughter.
我的傻女儿
What is it? Something bad happened?
什么事？发生什么事了？
They are going back.
他们要回去了
- Where? - Australia.
-去哪里？-澳大利亚
Immediately.
马上就走
Such a shame. You only just got back together.
真可惜  你们才团聚不久
She said "urgent". Did something bad happened?
她说“紧急”有什么不好的事吗？
- She made up with her husband. - That's nice.
-她和丈夫和好了-很好
That's good news.
那是好消息
It is so sudden.
太突然了
I've just gotten used to them.
我刚习惯他们
Is it alright if we leave tonight? I want to see them.
如果我们今晚离开可以吗？我想见他们
That's fine. I'll go and pack my suitcase.
没关系  我去收拾行李
Agah...
阿加
don't be upset.
不要难过
It was nice to have somebody around, a voice in the house.
有人在家里感觉很好
Now, I'll go back to being alone.
现在，我要回到孤独中去
I am ready. We can go.
我准备好了，我们可以走了
-We can leave right away. -No rush. Let's eat first.
-我们可以马上离开  -不要着急  让我们先吃饭
Then we can leave.
吃完再走
Boss...
老大
you can take it to the administrative court...
你可以上诉行政法院
even all the way to council of state.
甚至一直到州议会
There'll be no use.
没用了
What are you going to do?
你会怎样做？
First, I have to remove the sand bag. But it's not going to be easy.
首先，我要把沙袋搬走，但并不容易
Then I'll go and see may children.
然后我要去看看孩子
I'll say to them "daddy is back, I'll be home from now on".
我要对他们说：“爸爸回来了，从现在开始我就回家了”
"The never-ending shift has finally ended. Your dad is here now".
“无休止的加班终于结束了   你父亲现在回家了”
That's what I'll say to them. Then I'll go to sleep.
那就是我要对他们说的话  然后我去睡觉
This is the plan for time being.
这是暂时的计划
Do you want to know how I feel?
你想知道我的感觉吗？
There are things in life that you rely on when you are in trouble.
当你遇到麻烦时，生活中有些事情是你可以依靠的
For example, 155. Police emergency.
例如155紧急报警
Or if there is a fire, you know that fire brigade will attend.
或者如果发生火灾，你知道消防队会来
If you're stuck in an elevator you push the emergency button...
如果你被困在电梯中，按紧急按钮
and talk to someone.
就能求救
There are panic buttons.
有紧急按钮
You push them and talk to police or whoever.
你按下按钮，就能与任何警察交谈
All of these give you a piece of mind.
所有这些都让你心态平静下来
Just imagine that none of these works.
试想一下，这些都没用了
You dial 155 but no answer.
你拨155但无人接听
There is a fire. You call the fire brigade but no one shows up.
发生火灾你叫消防队，但没人出现
You are stuck in an elevator. You push the button to talk to someone.
你被困在电梯中  你按按钮求救
Panic button for example.
例如紧急按钮
You push it and shout "is there anybody there".
你按下它并大喊“有人在吗”
But no answer.
但是没有答案
You start to think there is something wrong.
你开始认为这按钮有问题
You snap it off the wall, take a look and...!
你把按钮从墙上拔下来  仔细一看
What the f... cuk!
什么鬼！
The wires are not connected.
没接电线
There are no wires. Just a thing that was mounted on the wall.
没有电线  只是墙上的摆设
You've spent your life by trusting it. But they put it there to deceive you.
你一生都相信它。但他们把它放在那里是为了欺骗你
Just trust it. Don't ask questions. Just do your job. That's what it is there for.
只要相信它，不要问问题，做你的工作，这就是它的目的
But you've been fool enough to trust it.
但是你已经傻到相信它了
There was nothing to trust. That's how I feel now.
没有什么可信任的了，这就是我现在的感觉
I believed in things for nothing. And that's what really bugs me.
我毫无意义的相信它，那才是真正困扰我的地方
I don't know what to do now.
我不知道现在该怎么办
All right lads...
好啦
you know, I always say to you...
你知道，我总是对你说……
our job...
我们的工作……
I mean your job...
我是说你们的工作……
is saving lives.
是拯救生命
That's why, there is no resting for you until the last killer is caught.
这就是为什么直到最后一个杀手被抓到之前你都无法休息
It means that you'll never rest.
这意味着你永远不会休息
Because there will always be a killer on the loose.
因为永远都会有一个杀手
You knowingly choose a difficult life, so that people you don't even know...
你故意选择艰难的生活，这样就可以让那些你不认识的人
can sleep peacefully in their beds.
可以在床上安静地睡觉
You swore to sacrifice your lives for people you don't know...
你发誓要为不认识的人牺牲生命
so justice in this sh... tty world can prevail.
因此在这个小小的世界里  正义就可以占上风
It was an honour to work with you guys.
和你们一起工作很荣幸
And you should be proud of yourselves.
而且你们应该为自己感到骄傲
Because...
因为……
dedicating a life to justice is not a personal matter.
把一生献给正义不是个人的事
It is the matter of personality.
这是人格的问题
Take care.
照顾好自己
S... t!
该死！
What do you want?
你想要什么？
Another fairy-tale? Is that why you're calling?
你要给我讲另一个童话故事吗？
You hung Reyhan's photo everywhere. It says on it "do you remember".
到处都挂着雷汉的照片，上面写着“你还记得吗”
What has it got to do with you?
和你有什么关系？
Find Sungur Demirci. He is the one who best remembers.
去找桑古尔·史密斯  他是最记得的人
He was pimping Reyhan.
他曾给雷汉拉皮条
Pimping?
拉皮条？
How do you know? My husband told me.
你怎么知道  我丈夫告诉我的
You were right Nevra. I married the man who raped me.
你是对的  内芙拉  我嫁给了强奸我的男人
Sefa...
塞法
is there a Sungur Demirci among men whom you investigate in Kambura?
你在坎布拉调查的人中是否有桑古尔·史密斯？
Sungur.
桑古尔
Let's see.
我找找
Sungur Demirci.
桑古尔·史密斯
We already took a statement from him.
我们已经从他那里获得证言了
- What does he do? - He said "marketing".
-他做什么的？-他说“营销”
We are going to Kambura.
我们要去坎布拉
Go on, pass.
继续  过去
Go on.
过去啊
Isn't he the...?
他是……？
Yes, that's him.
是的，就是他
Agah, can you slow down please?
阿加，你能放慢速度吗？
- We are already slow. - Make it slower please.
-我们已经慢了  -请慢一点
You know I don't like speed.
你知道我不喜欢速度
Agah!
阿加
I feel very uncomfortable. Please slow down.
我感到很不舒服  请放慢速度
There is a truck right ahead. What are you doing?
前面有一辆卡车你在做什么？
I want to get off. Are you alright Agah?
我要下车  你还好吗？
Can you pull over? I want to get off. I feel very uncomfortable.
你可以停下来吗？我想下车我感到很不舒服
Agah, please. I want to get off.
阿加，我要下车
What are you doing? Slow down. You're going to kill us.
你在做什么？慢点  你要害死我们
What are you doing? You're going to kill us.
你在做什么？你要害死我们
Agah!
阿加！
I apologize.
我道歉
You've made me relive the most horrific moment of my life.
你让我重温了我一生中最恐怖的时刻
- How could you? - I apologize.
-你怎么能这样？-我道歉
You are not what you appear to be. Who are you?
你的表现一点都不像你  你是谁
I don't want to know anyway. Just leave it at that.
反正我也不想知道  就这样吧
There is a saying...
有句话……
don't complain about the traffic. Because you are the traffic.
不要抱怨交通  因为你就是交通
You were not the only guilty party. I was guilty too.
你不是唯一有罪的  我也有罪
I wished that tango we had that night would last forever.
我希望我们那天晚上的探戈舞能永远持续下去
Let's dance forever. Let's tango forever.
让我们永远跳舞  让我们永远跳探戈
But the music had stopped long ago and I never knew it.
但是音乐很久以前就停止了，我一直不知道
I apologize.
我道歉
What is this? What's going on?
到底是怎么回事
Get out.
出去
I've been following you for hours and you knew it.
我已经跟着你几个小时了，你知道的
Don't pretend that you are surprized.
不要假装你很惊讶
Shut the door.
关上门
Easy.
放松
What do you want, money?
你想要什么，钱？
Amazing...
惊人……
eleven murders.
十一起谋杀案
What murder?
什么谋杀案
I must admit, you don't fit in the type.
我必须承认，你不适合这种类型
I don't know you.
我不认识你
You know rookie deputy superintendent Nevra.
你知道菜鸟副警长内芙拉
You keep texting her.
你一直留言给她
But you don't know Firuz, the fastest slinger in the whole homicide.
但是你不知道菲鲁兹，他是整个凶杀科中破案最快的人
Of course you know me. You know me like f... ck.
你当然知道我
Well done to you. I mean it.
你做的很好，我是说真的
This is how a serial killer should be.
这就是连环杀手应有的样子
He should know the cops who are after him...
他应该知道警察在追随他
so he can run.
这样他就可以逃跑
Can I see your badge?
我可以看一下你的徽章吗？
Who are you kidding? Me or yourself?
你在跟谁开玩笑？我还是你自己？
Or both of us?
还是我们俩？
Can I see your badge?
我可以看一下你的徽章吗？
Is it O.K?
可以吗？
Are you arresting me? Are we going down the station?
你要逮捕我吗？我们要去警察局吗？
We are going straight to the court.
我们直接上法庭
- What do you mean by court? - I mean you'll talk.
-法庭是什么意思？-我是说你会招供
You'll confess. You'll tell.
你会承认  你会交待
You used to work in the courthouse. You know how it goes.
你以前在法院工作  你知道程序
You'll talk and I'll listen.
你说我听着
I am not telling you anything.
我什么都没告诉你
You either take me down to the station or this is a kidnap.
你要么带我去警局，不然的话你这是绑架
Do you know the minimum?
你知道最低限度吗？
I don't think we can see eye to eye.
我认为我们的看法不一致
I am telling you, it is over.
我告诉你，结束了
You are caught. Understand?
你被抓了  懂吗？
I have 40 evidence that says Agah Beyoğlu killed all those people.
我有40个证据表明，阿加·贝尤鲁杀死了所有这些人
Now, it is about time you tell me why you are so interested in Kambura.
现在，是时候告诉我你为什么对坎布拉如此感兴趣了
I am not telling you anything.
我什么都没告诉你
You can take me down to the station and provide me with a lawyer.
你可以带我去警察局  给我找律师
Well, well, well.
好吧好吧
I think you've been watching too many movies.
我想你看了太多电影
I can provide you with somebody else instead of a lawyer.
我可以给你找别人代替律师
How about...
如果……
your daughter?
你女儿
Zuhal.
祖哈尔
How do you know Zuhal?
你怎么知道祖哈尔？
I have DNA analysis. And you are asking me how I know your daughter.
我有DNA分析报告，你问我怎么认识你女儿的
I know her from a different place. But it is a different subject.
我从其他地方认识她，但与这无关
What do you mean by different subject?
你所说的无关是什么意思？
How do you know Zuhal?
你怎么知道祖哈尔？
Shall we go and ask her in person?
我们可以亲自去问她吗？
She can sit right beside you...
她可以坐在你旁边
instead of a lawyer.
代替律师
She can sit very close to you.
她可以坐得很近
Then I shoot her in the head.
然后我爆了她的头
Her blood splashes on your face.
她的血溅在你的脸上
Perhaps you confess while your daughter's blood is running down...
也许在你女儿血在你脸上流淌的时候
your face.
你才会招供
What do you think?
你觉得怎么样？
Where do you think Zuhal is now? Home or work?
你觉得祖哈尔现在在哪里？在家还是在工作？
What do you want from me? Why are you doing this?
你想从我这里得到什么？为什么要这样做？
I've a little debt to pay off.
我有债务要还清
Who knows? I may even become a payee after all.
谁知道呢？我甚至可以成为收​​款人
If you do anything to Zuhal...
如果你对祖哈尔做任何事……
cause her any harm...
伤害她……
I'll make you suffer so much before I kill you...
在我杀死你之前，我会让你受尽苦难
you'd wish you were never born.
你会希望你从没有出生
Do you understand me son?
孩子你明白吗？
Yeah, sure.
当然
I am doing my deed...
我在做我的事情……
giving you a little warning.
给你一点警告
You are not going anywhere. What do you mean you're leaving?
你哪都不去  你说你要走是什么意思？
You're going nowhere. I won't let you.
你不能走  我不会让你走
Look...
听着……
you did me good. I won't let you go.
你对我很好  我不会让你走
Cemil, think sensibly.
塞米尔，好好思考一下
O.K, we have a thing going. But Deva has a future there.
好吧，我们之间有了火花，但是德瓦有一个未来
I have a house there.
我在那里有房子
I'll bring that house down Zuhal.
我把那房子搬过来  祖哈尔
What?
什么事？
O.K, that's good.
好  那很好
Where are you now?
你现在在哪里？
I'll be there right away.
我马上去
First, we have to sort out our own issues.
首先，必须解决我们的问题
Then I'll deliver the goods.
然后我再去送货
- What do you want? - We'll talk about it.
-你想要什么？-我们会谈的
Who is this man? What's his problem?
这个人是谁？他有什么问题？
I don't know. But we'll find out.
我不知道  但我们会找到答案的
I'll let you know if we come to a deal.
如果我们达成协议，我会让你知道的
B... stard!
畜生！
What is it, something bad?
什么事？坏事吗？
Yes, it is. He does exactly the same.
是的，他也是一样
Who is he? What's going on?
他是谁？怎么了？
You're all the same. First, you make me believe things.
你们都是一样的  首先，你让我相信一切
Then you betray me.
然后就背叛我
What did I do to you?
我对你做了什么？
Nothing but favours.
只有恩惠
Shame on you.
你太无耻了
You are nothing like your father.
你一点都不像你父亲
I hope whoever is behind this slander rots in hell.
我希望在这个在背地里诽谤的人在地狱里腐烂
I know nothing about pimping.
我对拉皮条一无所知
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Now Mr Sungur, if you're going to be all tensed up...
现在，桑古尔先生，如果你要全神贯注
we can take you down the station where you can relax a bit.
我们可以带你到警察局放松一下
Look, officers...
你看  长官……
I have nothing to do with pimping or anything.
我和拉皮条无关
Tell me, how did you manage to disguise yourself all these years?
告诉我，这些年来你如何掩饰自己？
You have no criminal record.
你没有犯罪记录
I wonder if you happen to know a judge or something.
我想知道你是否碰巧认识法官
For instance, Mehmet Yurtgil.
例如，穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔
- Do you know him? - No, I don't.
-你认识他吗？-不，我不知道
I don't know any judge.
我不认识任何法官
Nevra...
内芙拉
can you excuse us for a minute?
你能回避一下吗？
Look, I swear I know nothing. I don't know Reyhan or any other girl.
听着，我发誓我一无所知  我不认识雷汉或其他女孩
You can ask anybody.
你可以问任何人
I am not involved in anything like that.
我没有参与过这样的事情
We did ask. They said you are a pimp.
我们确实问过  他们说你就是皮条客
F... cking b..stards.
该死的畜生！
Yes, you're right. Unfortunately you can never trust people.
是的，你是对的  不幸的是你永远不能信任别人
I myself was a victim of a slander once. That's how I know.
我自己曾经是诽谤的受害者  那就是我的经验
Once, we detained a man who later claimed that we tortured him.
一次，我们拘留了一个人，他后来声称我们对他施加了酷刑
I said no way.
我说不可能
Son of a b... tch even got a report from a hospital...
那个畜生甚至从医院得到报告
claiming that we broke his bones.
声称我们打断了他的骨头
I said he probably did it himself.
我说他可能自己做的
Banging his arms and legs to a wall.
将他的胳膊和腿撞到墙上
He was planning to take us to court.
他打算把我们告上法庭
Luckily internal affairs ruled out investigation and the case closed.
幸运的是，内政排除了调查工作，案件结案
Appropriate outcome.
合理的结果
Yeah, otherwise. We would've been in deep shit.
是的，否则我们会陷入困境
That's why I understand you. Being falsely accused is a bad thing.
这就是为什么我了解你被错误指控是多么糟糕
Because I had not broken any bones.
因为我没有打断任何一根骨头
I had stuck a truncheon up his a..s instead.
我把警棍塞到他菊花里了
I think he was too ashamed to tell the doctors.
我觉得他可能很羞愧，无法告诉医生
I wouldn't be so upset if he told the truth.
如果他说了实话，我就不会那么心烦意乱了
But he was lying.
但是他说谎
He was saying I broke his arm.
他说我打断了胳膊
So, your wife has passed away.
那么你老婆去世了
Yes, she's gone. May she rest in peace.
是的，她走了  愿她安息
What do you do about cooking?
你如何做饭？
There is a girl. She comes around and does it for me.
有一个女孩  她过来为我做
Do you like pastry, like, pies and things?
你喜欢糕点，馅饼和东西吗？
- Yeah, I do. - Good.
-是的，我喜欢  -很好
So, you must have a rolling pin.
那么，你一定有一个擀面杖
O.K Mr Agah, spill the beans. What's your problem with Kambura?
好的，阿格先生，该交待了。你和坎布拉有什么瓜葛？
It was 1995.
1995年
I was transferred to Kambura Court House.
我被调到坎布拉法院
In the beginning everything was good.
一开始一切都很好
People were pleasant and hospitable.
人们愉快而热情好客
And Kambura was a nice place.
坎布拉是个很不错的地方
I said to my late wife that we came to a nice place...
我对我已故的妻子说我们来了一个好地方
that we are out of the hustle-bustle of Istanbul.
我们脱离了伊斯坦布尔的喧嚣
In 1996...
1996年
a 14 year old girl committed suicide.
一名14岁女孩自杀
She used to live with her granny.
她生前和奶奶住在一起
Poor girl was an orphan.
可怜的女孩是一个孤儿
Her name was Reyhan.
她的名字叫雷汉
I received the file.
我收到文件
The police report said "heavy depression".
警方报告称“重度抑郁症”
And the case was closed.
而且已经结案了
One day, her granny turned up, holding a notebook.
一天，她的奶奶来了，拿着一个笔记本
She said it belonged to her grandchild but couldn't read it as she was illiterate.
她说这是她的孙女的，但由于她是文盲看不懂
She said her grandchild wouldn't take her life in her own accord.
她说她的孙子不会无缘无故自杀
She said something must've happened to her.
她说她一定发生了什么事
She said it may be in this notebook. I want you to take a look.
她说可能在这个笔记本上  我要你看看
And so I did.
所以我看了
It was her diary.
那是她的日记
She'd written down everything.
她写下了一切
Every single name in Kambura was in the diary.
日记中坎布拉的每个名字
Even from outside.
甚至还有外人
For example, a judge.
例如法官
He used to visit Kambura every now and then.
他曾经不时拜访坎布拉
So, he knew too.
所以他也知道
Judges, teachers...
法官，老师……
crooks, cops...
骗子，警察……
poor and the rich...
穷人和富人……
the educated, the ignorant...
有文化的  没文化的……
She was only 12 years old at the time.
她当时只有12岁
Only 12.
只有12岁
- Reyhan stop. - Stay away.
-雷汉停下-别过来
Reyhan!
雷汉！
- Don't. - Away!
-不要-走开！
Reyhan, stop.
雷汉停下
Away!
走开！
Let me go.
放开我
For 2 years...
整整两年……
all these men raped the poor girl.
这些人都强奸过那个可怜的女孩
53 of them in total.
共53个人
The poor girl couldn't take it anymore and she took her own life.
这个可怜的女孩受不了了，她选择自杀
She'd become anybody's item.
她会成为任何人的泄欲工具
I don't know who but apparently a boy gives her a false hope of marriage.
我不知道是谁，但显然是一个男孩错误的给了她婚姻希望
He makes a move on her.
他对她采取了行动
She doesn't decline, thinking that they were going to get married anyway.
她不拒绝，以为他们无论如何都会结婚
Then he begins to threaten her, forcing her to be with others too.
然后他开始威胁她，迫使她也和别人在一起
She gets frightened.
她很害怕
She thinks it will be just a one-time thing.
她认为这只是一次性的事情
But the men keep coming, one after the other.
但是男人们源源不断，一个接一个
Like flies around honey.
像蜂蜜一样
Then they brought her to me.
然后他们把她带给我
I thought I could make some cash.
我以为我可以赚点钱
We have a barn just over there.
我们那边有一个谷仓
She worked for couple of months. Then she killed herself.
她工作了几个月，然后自杀了
You s..n of a b... tc!
你这个狗娘养的畜生！
I am going to ruin your f... cking life.
我要毁了你的生活
S..n of a b... tch!
畜生！
What did you do after reading the diary?
看完日记后你做了什么？
What can I do? I had an 11-year-old daughter.
我该怎么办？我有一个11岁的女儿
I thought I should move her away. So, I sent her to a boarding school.
我认为应该把她送走  所以我送她去了寄宿学校
She had to get out of Kambura. Because these men were everywhere.
她必须离开坎布拉，因为这些男人无处不在
What did you do about Reyhan?
你对雷汉做了什么？
Didn't you hand the diary over to D.A? No trial was set?
你不是将日记交给了检察长了吗？没有安排庭审吗？
I was going to hand it to the D.A. But his name was in the diary too.
我本来要交给检察长的，但是他的名字也在日记里
My hand was tied. I was scared.
我无能为力，我很害怕
There were so many of them. And I was just a simple civil servant.
他们人太多了，我只是一个小小的公务员
I thought they can walk all over me.
我以为他们把我踏平
The girl was gone anyway. What's the use of taking the case to the court?
无论如何，那个女孩已经死了，将案件提交法院又能怎样？
It was not going to bring her back.
不会把她带回来
F..cking sh... t!
该死！
After a while, I got transferred to Istanbul.
过了一段时间，我转到了伊斯坦布尔
But I never forgot about Reyhan.
但我从未忘记雷汉
I left Kambura. But I was never able to leave Reyhan.
我离开了坎布拉，但我再也无法放下雷汉
10 years ago, I bought a gun.
10年前，我买了枪
I wanted to kill someone.
我想杀人
I tried but failed.
我尝试过但是失败了
I tried again...
我再次尝试……
but failed again.
但又失败了
What made you start killing them all?
是什么让你开始杀死所有人？
I was diagnosed with Alzheimer's Disease.
我被诊断出患有阿尔茨海默氏病
I thought to myself "you are running out of time".
我对自己说：“你没时间了”
It will come a day you'll forget about Reyhan.
总有一天，你会忘掉雷汉
You'll forget about Reyhan who has been in your mind for 22 years.
你会忘记这个在你的脑海中已有22年的雷汉
Was Cemil Havran in the diary too? Is that why you went to him?
塞米尔·哈夫兰也在日记中吗？这就是你去找他的原因？
Whole of Kambura took care of him.
整个坎布拉都照顾过他
Business owners, civil servants.
企业主，公务员
I even paid for son of a b... tch's private lessons.
我甚至还为那个畜生支付了私人课程的费用
It turned out that he was pimping the girl to return the favours.
结果，他给女孩拉皮条，以回报众人的恩惠。
Most names in the diary belonged to those who helped Cemil.
日记中的大多数名字都属于那些帮助过塞米尔的人
Just give me a f... cking break.
让我喘口气
Hello?
喂？
I am listening doctor.
我在听  医生
O.K, we'll be on our way.
好，我们这就出发
I am bringing him.
我带他一起
Are we going?
我们要走了吗？
Come on.
来吧
- You are staying here. - What?
-你待在这里-什么？
Why are you not taking me?
你为什么不带我走？
Take me to the station.
带我去警察局
Why are you leaving me here? Firuz!
你为什么要离开我这里？ 菲鲁兹！
Why did you leave me here?
你为什么把我留在这里？
I told Nevra everything.
我已经告诉了内芙拉一切
But she doesn't believe me.
但她不相信我
Wish they all die.
希望他们都死了
They are, Reyhan.
他们都死了  雷汉
Don't you worry about it.
你不用担心了
All dying.
都快死了
Hello?
喂？
I want to ask you something.
我想问你点事儿
In Naz Çörtük's case, there was a drop of blood on the floor...
在纳兹·切尔图克的案子中，地板上有一滴血
but away from the victim.
但离受害者较远
As if it belonged to somebody else.
看起来像是别人的
It may belong to the killer.
血迹可能属于杀手
Has anything come out of it?
有什么结果吗？
Drop of blood?
一滴血？
There was no such a thing in the report.
报告中没有这样的事情
It is not in your report. But I can see it in the photo.
不在你的报告中，但我可以在照片中看到
I told you I was there before the cops arrived.
我告诉过你我在警察来之前我就到了
It keeps boggling my mind. I thought I'd ask you.
这件事一直困扰着我。我想问问你。
- Where are you anyway? - Kambura.
-总之你在哪里？-坎布拉
I'll drop by tomorrow and take the photo from you before I go the station.
我明天去警局前顺便去区照片
O.K.
好
- Nevra? - What?
-内芙拉？-什么？
I love you.
我爱你
Nevra?
内芙拉？
I think I am standing outside the house we once lived years ago.
我想我站在我们几年前曾经住过的房子门口
Can I call you later Ateş?
我可以稍后再打给你吗？
O.K.
好
Did you check your room Nevra? Make sure you got everything.
你检查房间了吗？内芙拉  确保你带齐东西
I got everything mum.
我都带了  妈妈
I'll return the key to the landlord. Then we can get going.
我把钥匙交给房东  然后我们就可以离开了
I am going to meet Reyhan. I want to see her for the last time.
我要去见雷汉  我想最后在见她一面
Go on. But don't be late.
去吧  但是不要太久
O.K.
好
We've got a long way to go. I want to get there before the evening.
我们还有很长的路要走  我想在晚上之前到达那里
Nevra?
内芙拉？
Come with me.
跟我来
We are leaving. Mum told me not to be late.
我们要走了  妈妈告诉我不要迟到
We'll make it quick.
我们会很快的
Where are we going?
我们去哪？
I am going to meet him in the woods. I want you to meet him.
我要在树林里见他  我想让你也见见他
But you can't tell anybody, O.K?
但是你不能告诉任何人，好吗？
O.K, promise. Come on.
好，我答应你
Firuz!
菲鲁兹！
Who is there?
谁在那儿？
Anybody there?
有人在吗？
Firuz...
菲鲁兹
son...
孩子……
why are you keeping me here?
你为什么要把我留在这里？
Take me to the station, arrest me and let's get on with it.
带我去警局，逮捕我吧
Shut up!
闭嘴！
Don't talk.
不要说话
The last one...
最后一个
for the last time.
最后一次
What?
什么？
You will kill for the last time.
你会再杀最后一个人
Who?
谁？
Cemil.
塞米尔
Son, are you alright?
孩子你还好吗
And I'll never hear your name again.
然后我就再也不会听到你的名字
Or I'll come to your house...
不然我就去你家
and rip your heart out.
把你的心掏出来
Do you understand?
你明白了吗？
If you get caught, I don't know you.
如果被你抓住了，我不认识你
If you don't get caught...
如果你不被抓住
I'll forget about you, and you'll forget about me.
我会忘记你，你也会忘记我
I killed so many people. It was all over the papers.
我杀了这么多人，报纸上到处都是
Police will never stop chasing me.
警察永远不会停止抓捕我
You...
你
do you think you are the only one with Alzheimer's Disease?
你认为你是唯一患有阿尔茨海默氏病的人吗？
Everybody is sick.
所有人都有病
They're all sick.
他们都病了
Come an international match, everybody will forget about everything.
来一场国际比赛，每个人都会忘记一切
This nation forgot so many things.
这个国家忘记了很多事情
You won't be an exception.
你也不会例外
Who do you think you are anyway?
你认为你是谁？
You are just a killer, a murder case in the news.
你只是杀手，新闻中的谋杀案
Why are you doing this?
你为什么做这个？
Cemil...
塞米尔
he owns a hospital.
他有一家医院
My son is being treated there since he was born.
我儿子从出生开始就接受治疗
It doesn't cost me a penny.
我一分钱都不花
Cemil wouldn't do anything for nothing.
塞米尔不会白做的
True.
是的
He got me in return.
他要我回报他
I made a promise to myself.
我对自己做了一个承诺
I said, if something happens to my son...
我说，如果我儿子出事了
Cemil will die.
塞米尔也会死
My son...
我的儿子……
my son died today.
我儿子今天死了
He was unable to leave the operating table alive.
他没能活着下手术台
Now...
现在……
I'll call Cemil.
我打电话给塞米尔
I'll tell him that you escaped.
我告诉他你逃走了
I won't reveal your I.D.
我不会透露你的身份证
Now, go and kill him.
现在，去杀死他
And then, disappear.
然后消失
- I will have another gift in my hand. - What is it?
-我手里还有另一个礼物-是什么？
Then I'll ask your granddad.
那我问你爷爷
Good morning.
早上好
I was trying to call you.
我想打电话给你
I have to leave.
我得走了
I'll meet ex-chief Tolga.
我要会见前局长托尔加
Chief Tolga?
托尔加局长？
-Are you in touch with him?- I'll tell you all about it.
-你和他有联系吗？-我会把一切都告诉你的
Shall we meet at the same café tomorrow?
明天我们可以在同一个咖啡馆见面吗？
The one near you.
你家附近的那个
Alright.
好的
Fine.
好
Ateş!
阿提斯！
The photo?
照片？
Sorry.
抱歉
I made coffee for you. There is food too.
我为你了煮咖啡  还有早餐
Eat before you go.
出发前先吃饭
I can help myself. Thanks.
不用担心我 谢谢
See you.
再见
Ateş!
阿提斯
I found something Nevra.
我发现了一些东西  内芙拉
Something very big.
很大的东西
But I have to tell Tolga first. Is that O.K?
但是我必须先告诉托尔加  好吗？
Ateş!
阿提斯！
I love you too.
我也爱你
Oh, yeah!
哦耶！
Nevra!
内夫拉！
Life is good.
生活真美好
1 Week Later.
1周后
Where?
哪里？
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
Is this earthquake? What is it?
这是地震吗？
It is night already. I went to bed in the afternoon.
已经是晚上了  我下午就上床了
The time...
几点了
half past two.
两点半
I must've been sleeping for ages.
我一定睡了好久了
Bloody music is still going.
音乐还在继续
They are bouncing up and down like donkeys.
他们像驴一样上下跳动
I've had enough of this s... it.
我已经受够了
Nevra Elmas, the only female detective in homicide...
内夫拉·埃尔玛斯，凶杀科唯一的女侦探
handed her resignation today.
今天递交辞呈
She was one of the most mediatic faces of the police force.
她是警察队伍中最吸引人的面孔之一
The reason behind her decision is not known yet.
她辞职的原因尚不清楚
I said everything will be turned off by 2 a.m.
我说过一切都要在2点停止
What is this, a nightclub?
这是什么？夜总会？
What is this?
这是什么？
- I got it for you today. - Why?
-我今天买给你的-为什么？
We are leaving dad. You'll be here all alone.
我们要离开了  爸爸  你会一个人在家里
It will be a company for you.
它将陪伴你
I can't believe all that happened while I was asleep.
我不敢相信我睡着时发生的所有事情
Everybody must've been waiting for this.
每个人肯定都在等着
You have been asleep for ages. I didn't want to wake you up.
你已经睡了好久了  我不想唤醒你
It must've been an exhausting vacation with Miss Nükhet.
一定是和努凯特小姐度过了令人筋疲力尽的假期
Do you think it is the medication that is making you sleepy?
你认为是药物使你困倦的吗？
They say it can make you feel sleepy.
他们说这会让你感到困
Where are you going dad?
爸爸你要去哪里
There was a photo of me and your mum over there. Where did you put it?
那里有我和你的妈妈的照片，你放在哪里了？
It is still here.
还在这里
I moved it back to its old place.
我把它搬回了原来的地方
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
Downstairs. To find out what the hell is going on.
楼下  我去看看到底发生了什么
Deva and his friends are having a farewell party.
德瓦和他的朋友们举行了欢送会
They are enjoying themselves. Leave them.
他们玩的正开心，让他们玩吧
They can enjoy themselves somewhere else.
他们可以在其他地方玩
Do I go to their house and bounce up and down?
我会去他们的房子跳来跳去吗？
Bloody hell! What a waste of a generation.
真是一代废人！
She got me a TV.
她给我买了一台电视
As if I am not capable of getting one myself.
好像我没有能力自己买一样
I don't want it. Simple as that.
我不想要  仅此而已
Look at that. They shut the door supposedly keep the noise in.
你看看  他们关上了门，据说是为了防止噪音
It is f... cking full blast. It's going to bring the whole building down.
简直就是爆炸  会把整栋楼都拆了
Open it.
开门
What's going on here?
这里发生了什么？
Why are you dressed like this?
你怎么这样穿
Deva!
德瓦！
Is Deva here?
德瓦在这里吗？
Deva!
德瓦！
Let me through.
让我过去
How dare you call me bitch?
你怎么敢叫我婊子
You are the bitch.
你才是婊子
I am not a bitch.
我不是婊子
You are the bitch.
你才是婊子
Afşin!
阿夫辛！
Are you alright?
你还好吗？
Afşin, are you alright?
阿夫辛，你还好吗？
Don't just stand there.
不要只是站在那里
Call an ambulance. Come on.
叫救护车来吧
It is terrible.
太糟了
How could she do something like this?
她怎么能这样
She was a such a sweet girl.
她是一个如此可爱的女孩
- How is the boy?  - A minor wound.
-他还好吗？-轻伤
The paramedic said it is not life threatening.
医护人员说这不会威胁生命
In this case, she may as well shoot him again.
在这种情况下，她不妨再次向他射击
How come such a young girl can get hold of a gun?
这么年轻的女孩怎么会拿着枪？
Who gave it to her?
谁送给她的？
Apparently, it was her dad's.
显然是她爸爸的
She should've shot her dad then. Like that boy did once.
那她也应该给她爸爸来一枪
Nothing.
没有
I think my blood pressure shot up. I am going.
我想我的血压升高了  我走了
- Are you alright dad? - I am O.K. I just don't feel too well.
-爸爸你还好吗？-我很好，只是感觉不太舒服
I just need a little rest. Come on.
我只需要休息一下
I said I am O.K.
我说我没事
Me and Deva share a secret.
我和德瓦分享了一个秘密
We have a secret.
我们有一个秘密
Don't ever forget me Deva.
永远不要忘记我  德瓦
Don't ever forget me.
永远不要忘记我
There you go.
走吧
Have a nice journey.
一路顺风
No crying.
不要哭
Take really good care of yourself dad. Don't forget to take your medication.
爸爸要好好照顾自己  不要忘了服药
No, I won't. Don't worry.
不会的 别担心
Deva!
德瓦！
Son!
孩子！
Have a nice journey.
一路顺风
I am sorry grandad.
对不起爷爷
Don't worry about it. It happens, doesn't it?
不用担心  事情已经发生了，不是吗？
It wasn't your fault.
不是你的错
What do you mean it wasn't my fault? I was the reason for it all.
你是什​​么意思不是我的错  这一切都是因为我
You weren't the reason for anything.
不是因为你
You didn't do anything. You didn't give her the gun.
你什么也没做  你没给她枪
The girl is sick, very sick.
这个女孩病了，病得很重
But no one had noticed. Even her own family.
但是没有人注意到  甚至她自己的家人
How would you have known?
你怎么知道的？
Apparently, she has been asking for help for years.
显然，她多年来一直在寻求帮助
By not talking to anyone, she was trying to say "I have a problem".
通过不与任何人交谈，试图说“我有问题”
But no one noticed.
但没人注意到
Whatever.
无所谓了
Have a safe journey.
旅途平安
I apologize.
我向你道歉
No crying. You'll make me cry too.
不要哭  你也会让我哭的
Come on, get in the car.
来吧，上车
Dad.
爸
I thank you ever so much.
我非常感谢你
Why? What happened?
怎么了
If it wasn't for you, there was no way I could've got rid of Cemil.
如果不是你的话，我绝对不可能摆脱塞米尔
We sat down, had a conversation and sorted it all out. That's it.
我们坐下来，进行了交谈，并把所有信息整理了出来。
Simple as that.
就那么简单
Mistakes are part of our lives. Everybody makes mistakes.
错误是我们生活的一部分  每个人都会犯错
Now, go on home. Take the nice memories with you.
现在，回家吧  带上美好的回忆
And tell your husband, if he gives you hard time again, I am here.
告诉你的丈夫，如果他再给你不好过，我在这里
- But I can't make it next time. - Next time, I'll come over there.
-但是下回我可能不会过来了-下回，我会去你那里
O.K, off you go. Have a safe journey.
好，出发了！旅途安全
O.K, we can go.
好  我们可以走了
Staying away from your daughter for years...
远离你的女儿多年
sending her to a boarding school so that she wouldn't get mixed up...
送她去寄宿学校，这样她就不会与塞米尔这类人
with the likes of Cemil.
混在一起
And what happens? In a big jungle like Istanbul, she somehow ends up with him.
结果怎样？在像伊斯坦布尔这样的大丛林中，她以某种方式最终与他走到一起
This is the price you pay for keeping quiet years ago.
这是你几年前保持沉默所要付出的代价
1 Week Later.
1周后
Nevra.
内芙拉
There is a delivery for you.
有一个快递给你
Come on darling, get up.
来吧亲爱的，起来
-I made you something to eat. -I am not hungry.
-我给你做了吃的  -我不饿
Come on.
来吧
You'll make yourself ill.
你会生病的
Come on.
来吧
Uskumru Street, Mebrure Blocks Flat No:8 Beyoğlu.
乌斯库姆鲁街，梅布鲁雷街区8号公寓贝尤鲁
Door Lock Combination:1682.
门锁密码：1682
Be there tomorrow morning.
明天早上到那里
I met a girl today. He name is Nevra Elmas.
我今天遇到一个女孩，他叫内芙拉·埃尔马斯
Today, 18th March.
今天，3月18日
It is Nevra's birthday. I got her a present.
这是内夫拉的生日，我给她准备了一份礼物
Me and Nevra share a secret.
我和内芙拉分享了一个秘密
Last night, I saw a shooting-star. And I made a wish.
昨晚，我看到了一颗流星，我许了一个愿望
I wish they all die.
我希望他们都死了
Save me Nevra.
救救我内芙拉
Naimhan came around again today.
奈汉今天又来了
Salih beat me up.
萨利赫殴打我
Today, Nevra left Kambura.
今天，内芙拉离开了坎布拉
I wanted her to meet Vural before she moved away.
我想要她在离开之前见见乌拉尔
I wanted my best friend to see the person whom I'll marry.
我希望我最好的朋友见见我要未来的丈夫
I am going to meet him in the woods. I want you to meet him.
我要在树林里见他  我想让你也见见他
So, we went to the woods.
所以，我们去了树林
But once there, Vural said something really bad.
但是到了那里，乌拉尔说的话真的很恶心
He said "now that Reyhan kissed you, would she kiss me too".
他说：“现在雷汉已经吻了你，她也会吻我吗？”
Her only objective is to be a good cop and a good human being.
她唯一的目标是成为一个好警察和一个好人
Then Cemil came.
然后塞米尔来了
Will you not talk to me Reyhan?
你不会和我说话吗？雷汉
I think she swallowed her tongue.
我想她把舌头咽下去了
Oh, look who is here.
哦，看看谁在这里
Is she your friend?
她是你的朋友吗？
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
She is cute too.
她也很可爱
Come on, let's leave the lovebirds alone.
来吧，让我们离开这对恋人
Let's take a walk.
我们出去走走
Nevra!
内芙拉！
Come on.
来吧
Let's sit somewhere.
我们找个地方坐下
I've never seen you around. Where are you from?
我从没见过你  你来自哪里？
Then Cemil appeared. And I never saw Nevra again.
然后塞米尔出现了，我再也见不到内芙拉了
I hope Cemil hadn't done anything bad to Nevra.
我希望塞米尔不会对内芙拉做任何坏事
Cemil.
塞米尔
Kill.
杀
Where have you been?
你去哪儿了？
You left the door open too.
你没锁门
You look such a mess. Where do you play, in woods?
你看起来一团糟  你在树林里玩什么？
Nevra?
内芙拉？
Darling?
亲爱的？
Has something happened?
发生什么事了吗？
Nevra?
内芙拉？
Darling?
亲爱的？
Nevra?
内芙拉？
Answer me darling. Has something happened?
亲爱的，回答我  发生什么事了？
No mum. Nothing happened.
没事  妈妈  什么都没发生
Darling?
亲爱的？
Cemil Havran will be available to be killed tonight at 9 o'clock.
塞米尔·哈夫兰将于今晚9点被杀
Hello Nevra.
你好  内芙拉
I am Agah Beyoğlu.
我是阿加·贝尤鲁
It looks good on you.
你看起来不错
You can take the head off. There are no cameras here.
你可以摘下头套了  这里没有监控
They are not fitted yet.
他们还没装
It can get too hot in there. I know it too well.
会很热的  我很清楚
I remembered.
我想起来了
I remembered everything.
我都想起来了
I am elated.
我很高兴
Because I had begun to forget.
因为我已经开始忘记了
I have a little health problem. I'll tell you later.
我有一个小的健康问题，我稍后再告诉你
I thought, this girl's not doing anything. May be, she doesn't remember.
我以为，这个女孩什么都没做，可能她不记得了
Despite me sending her messages.
尽管我已经向她发送了消息
I thought, may be Cemil didn't do anything to her.
我想也许是塞米尔没有对她做任何事情
I mean, I prayed to God that he didn't.
我的意思是，我向上帝祈祷，他没有做
But when I read about what he did to Reyhan...
但是当我读到他对雷汉做了什么时
I thought, almost certainly that he must've hurt Nevra too.
我想，几乎可以肯定，他也一定也伤害过内夫拉
But Nevra doesn't remember. She erased the memory.
但是内夫拉不记得了  她抹掉了这段记忆
And for the right reasons too.
而且出于正确的原因
You must've been so frightened.
你一定很害怕
I think we'd go insane if we remembered everything that we've been through.
我想如果我们想起经历过的一切，一定会发疯
But sometimes, remembering is the best way to keep one's sanity.
但是有时候，记住是保持理智最好的方法
Whatever.
随你
Now that you remember...
现在既然你想起来了……
it means that I can forget with peace of mind.
这意味着我可以放心地忘记了
Why is there nobody here? Why is the place empty?
为什么这里没有人？为什么这个地方空着？
It is not completed. It requires a little more work.
还没完工  还需要一点时间
That's what Cemil said. He is the financier.
这是塞米尔说的，他是财阀
He said "the place is empty at night. I'll take you there, show you the fish".
他说：“晚上这个地方是空的，我带你去那里，给你看鱼”
I said "O.K, take me there, let's see the fish.".
我说：“好，带我去，看看鱼”
It's amazing, isn't it? Kids will love it.
这真是太神奇了  孩子们都会喜欢的
Very nice.
非常好
So, you had no problem getting in, did you?
所以，你没问题，对吗？
You used the entrance that I told you. I had left the door open for you.
我告诉你了地址  并为你打开了门
Yes, that's right.
是的
Do you know what happened?
你知道发生了什么吗？
I said to myself...
我对自己说
stay out of it. She can do it alone.
别管她  她自己可以的
Than I thought, it'd be like trying to learn to swim.
然后我想了想  就如同学习游泳
Like jumping off from a jetty.
就像从码头跳下来一样
I thought I should be with her when she makes her debut.
当她初次登台时，我认为我应该和她在一起
I think it was a wise decision. Don't you think?
我认为这是一个明智的决定，不是吗？
You almost got lost, heading in wrong direction.
你差点迷路，朝错误的方向前进
- Have you ever met Reyhan? - No.
-你见过雷汉吗？-没有
Never met her.
从未见过她
But I read that diary so many times...
但是我读了很多遍她的日记
I think I know Reyhan better than I know myself.
我想我比了解自己更了解她
Cemil's bodyguards are outside. You must've seen them.
塞米尔的保镖在外面  你一定看到了他们
And there is the security as well.
还有保安
Before they begin to barge in, I think we should make our move.
在他们开始进场之前，我认为我们应该采取行动
Come on.
来吧
This way.
这边
Come.
来
Nevra...
内芙拉
come.
来吧
This way.
这边
Cemil is here.
塞米尔在这里
Come on.
来吧
How could you...
你怎么能……
how could you do it?
你怎么能这样？
What's up?
这是怎么回事？
I can't do it.
我做不到
I thought I could, but...
我以为可以，但是……
I can't kill another human being.
我不能杀人
But he is not human.
但是他不是人
He is a monster.
他是一个怪物
No.
不
This is wrong.
这样不对
I was in the police force.
我曾是一名警察
This man should be arrested...
这个人应该被逮捕
should be tried.
应该被关起来
No, no. I think you are confused.
不，不，我想你很困惑
He should be locked up.
他应该被锁起来
You have to differentiate law and justice.
你必须区分法律和正义
They are two different things.
这是两个不同的东西
What you've just said is how it should be done in accordance with the law.
你刚才说的应该是如何依法治死
Of course, providing that there is law.
当然  只要有法律
But justice is something different.
但是正义是不同的
This is the justice.
这是正义
What is justice anyway?
总之正义是什么？
Self-defence?
自卫？
Revenge?
复仇？
Or belated self-defence?
还是迟来的自卫？
This man ruined your life.
这个人毁了你的生活
For example, think...
例如，你想一想
if you had a gun that day...
如果那天你有枪
you would've shot Cemil to defend yourself, wouldn't you?
你会射杀塞米尔来捍卫自己，不是吗？
Yes, you would. That's right.
是的，你一定会的
Then or now. What is the difference?
那时或现在有什么区别？
Then, you didn't have gun. But now, you have one.
那时你没有枪  但是现在你有一把
That's not why I became a cop.
那不是我成为警察的原因
That's exactly why you became a cop.
这正是你成为警察的原因
You were neither able to save Reyhan, nor yourself.
你既无法拯救雷汉，也无法拯救自己
That's why you decided to become a cop. It is so obvious.
这很明显就是你决定成为警察的原因
I just...
我只是……
I just wanted to be a good person.
我只是想成为一个好人
That's what I want too, my dear child.
那也是我想要的，亲爱的孩子
I want to be a good person, too.
我也想成为一个好人
This is a matter of life and death.
这是生死攸关的问题
He will die...
他会死……
and we will live.
我们将生存下去
This is no justice.
这是不公正的
It is a murder.
这是谋杀
In this case, I'll help you make a decision.
在这种情况下，我会帮助你做出决定
Put the gun down.
放下枪
You have to make a choice.
你必须做出选择
You have to kill either me or him.
你要杀了我或者杀了他
Or I'll kill him right now.
不然我马上杀了他
Are you going to kill someone who committed tens of murders...
你要杀死一个犯下数十起谋杀案的人
or the man who hurt you in most horrible way?
还是曾伤害过你的人？
This man ruined your life.
这个人毁了你的生活
These people ruined Reyhan's life.
这些人毁了雷汉的生活
Reyhan is dead. But they are still alive.
雷汉死了，但他们还活着
So, we might as well die and let them live, what do you think?
因此，不妨我们去死让他们活下去，你觉得怎么样？
This is a matter of life and death.
这是生死攸关的问题
Now...
现在
I'll count to three...
我要数三下
then I'll shoot Cemil.
然后我就去射杀塞米尔
But who knows, you may pull the trigger before I do.
但是谁知道呢，你可以在我做之前先开枪
I begin to count.
我开始数数
One.
一
Two.
二
1 Year Later.
一年后
Hi dad.
嗨老爸
Hello darling.
你好亲爱的
How is the little one? Give him to me, will you?
小孩子怎么样？给我抱抱，好吗？
He only just fell asleep.
他只是睡着了
Where is your mum?
你妈妈在哪
She is home.
她在家
She is exhausted, trying to look after Ateş.
她精疲力尽，在照顾阿提斯
I told her not to come.
我告诉她不要来
Fine. Say hello.
代我问好
I will.
我会的
- She said hello too. - Bless her.
-给她也问好-祝福她
How is he?
他怎么样？
What do you think?
你觉得呢？
Same.
老样子
Hi Uncle Agah.
你好  阿加叔叔
Look what I got.
看我得到了什么
We'll put Miss Mebrure's photo in it.
我们要把梅布鲁雷夫人的照片放进去
Why didn't you put the TV on?
为什么不打开电视？
It broke down again. It keeps breaking down.
它又坏了  总是坏
We're waiting for the repairman.
我们正在等待修理工
I am pregnant. What if I have a baby girl?
我怀孕了，如果我生了一个女孩怎么办？
I'd rather die than having a daughter.
我宁愿死也不要生一个女儿
Don't be afraid baby. You're not going to be born.
别怕宝贝  你不会出生
I will die.
我会死的